MUSTAPHA LATEB

Website: mlateb.github.io | GitHub: mlateb

Email: mustapha.lateb@gmail.com Adress: Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria Phone: +213 552 413 491

INTRODUCTION

Graduated, both, in **Ecology** and in **Geoinformation**. My research is mainly on Landcover change and forest fire mapping using satellite Remote Sensing and GIS.

Fan of **Data science**, I like to investigate new Image Processing, Machine Learning, Statistics and Timeseries Analysis techniques.

My most used tools are Python and its Geospatial libraries, QGIS, Bash, SQL, HTML, CSS and Git.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Jan 2017-Jun 2019: **Researcher** at the *Geoinformation in Environmental Management* departement, *Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania MAICh*.
- Mar 2013-Sep 2013: Energy Steward at Aldaph-NovoNordisk, Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria
- Nov 2011-Feb 2013 : Quality Assurance Technician at Aldaph-NovoNordisk, Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria

EDUCATION

- 2016 current : *Doctoral candidate*, **Geoinformation applied to Plant Ecology**, Mouloud Mammeri University of Tizi-Ouzou MMTO, Algeria *Topic:* Multitemporal landcover mapping
- 2013 2016: M. Sc. Degree (2 years), Geoinformation in Environmental Management, MAICh, Greece
 Thesis topic: "Development of an object-based classification model for monitoring treeline shifting, using aerial photography"
- 2011-2014: Magister degree (2 years), Applied Plant Ecology and Environmental Management, UMMTO, Algeria
 Thesis topic: "Study of oak hybridisation using Geometric Morphometric (Landmark Method)"
- 2006 2011 : *Ingénieur d'Etat (5 years)*, **Plant ecology and Environment** UMMTO, Algeria *Thesis topic*: "Inventory of oak gallings and evaluation their impact on forest stands"
- 2008 2011 : Senior Technician (3 years), Database Management INSFP, Algeria Thesis topic: " Creation of a Dynamic Website "

ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS

I was member of the organising committee of the two following international conferences:

- 38th Annual EARSeL Symposium on Earth Observation Supporting Sustainability Research 9-12 July 2018 Chania, Crete, Greece
- 11th EARSeL Forest Fires SIG Workshop on New Trends in Forest Fire Research Incorporating Big Data and Climate Change Modeling 25-27 September 2017, Chania, Greece

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Geospatial processing: Python (MITx 6.00.1x certificate) (Rasterio, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, geopandas, Shapely, ...)
- Version controle: Git
- Database: SQL
- Web design: HTML , CSS , $\mathsf{Markdown}$ Softwares: QGIS , $\mathsf{eCognition}$, ArcGIS , ERDAS , $\mathsf{MapInfo}$
- Operating systems: Linux & Windows

LANGUAGES

Kabyle: Mother tongue English: TOEFL ITP French: Fluent Arabic: Fluent Greek: Beginner